interface idiomObj {
	idiom: string;
	definition: string;
	question: string;
	a: string;
	b: string;
	c: string;
	d: string;
	correct: string;
}

export const idioms: idiomObj[] = [
	{
		idiom: 'in the red',
		definition:
			'If a person or organization is in the red, they owe money to someone or to another organization.',
		question:
			"I have so many outstanding parking tickets that I'll be in the  _____  if I pay them all off at once!",
		a: 'blue',
		b: 'red',
		c: 'green',
		d: 'black',
		correct: 'red',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'be yellow',
		definition: 'To be cowardly.',
		question:
			"I'm not surprised that Tom didn't come to the rally — he’s too  _____  to defend his beliefs in public.",
		a: 'yellow',
		b: 'red',
		c: 'white',
		d: 'velvet',
		correct: 'yellow',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'cry blue murder',
		definition: 'To scream or shout very loudly.',
		question:
			'Erika cried  _____  murder when she noticed the snake in the rocks next to her.',
		a: 'orange',
		b: 'black',
		c: 'red',
		d: 'blue',
		correct: 'blue',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'the black sheep of the family',
		definition: 'The worst member of the family.',
		question:
			"Mary is the  _____  sheep of the family. She's always in trouble with the police.",
		a: 'silver',
		b: 'brown',
		c: 'black',
		d: 'red',
		correct: 'black',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'have green fingers',
		definition:
			'If someone has green fingers, they are very good at gardening.',
		question:
			"My mom can keep any plant alive, even ones that I've nearly killed—she seriously has  _____  fingers.",
		a: 'green',
		b: 'gold',
		c: 'violet',
		d: 'blue',
		correct: 'green',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'see pink spiders',
		definition:
			'To hallucinate or see things incorrectly due to acute alcohol intoxication or withdrawal.',
		question:
			"You're going to start seeing  _____  spiders if you don't stop drinking so much.",
		a: 'pink',
		b: 'white',
		c: 'dark',
		d: 'black',
		correct: 'pink',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'born in/to the purple',
		definition:
			'Born into royalty. Purple is a color traditionally associated with royalty.',
		question:
			'Did you see pictures of the latest addition to the royal family? What a sweet little princess born to the  _____  !',
		a: 'yellow',
		b: 'green',
		c: 'purple',
		d: 'blue',
		correct: 'purple',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'gray divorce',
		definition:
			'Divorce between older couples (i.e., those who have gray hair).',
		question:
			'Obviously, there is a trend of  _____  divorces; the question is, why do people want to split up after 30 or more years of marriage?',
		a: 'silver',
		b: 'gray',
		c: 'light',
		d: 'white',
		correct: 'gray',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'do up brown',
		definition:
			'To do something to the maximum degree or with the maximum effect or impact.',
		question:
			'Of course she decorated the room beautifully for the birthday party—she does everything up  _____  .',
		a: 'red',
		b: 'blue',
		c: 'black',
		d: 'brown',
		correct: 'brown',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'the white hope',
		definition:
			'The person or thing expected to bring great success or fortune to someone or something.',
		question:
			"Many are talking about the rising football star as the team's  _____  hope.",
		a: 'pink',
		b: 'orange',
		c: 'white',
		d: 'silver',
		correct: 'white',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'turn green with envy',
		definition: 'To become very jealous of another person.',
		question:
			"My son turns  _____  with envy whenever his sister gets something and he doesn't.",
		a: 'green',
		b: 'black',
		c: 'yellow',
		d: 'brown',
		correct: 'green',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'the yellow brick road',
		definition:
			'A course of action that a person takes believing that it will lead to good things',
		question:
			'Jenna took the internship thinking that she was following the  _____  brick road to her dream job.',
		a: 'white',
		b: 'blue',
		c: 'yellow',
		d: 'gold',
		correct: 'yellow',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'a red herring',
		definition:
			'Something irrelevant that diverts attention away from the main problem or issue.',
		question:
			'The book is fast-paced, exciting, and full of  _____  herrings.',
		a: 'red',
		b: 'green',
		c: 'black',
		d: 'violet',
		correct: 'red',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'out of the blue',
		definition: 'Completely unexpectedly',
		question:
			'She had no idea that anything was wrong until he announced out of the  _____  that he wanted a divorce.',
		a: 'white',
		b: 'black',
		c: 'blue',
		d: 'red',
		correct: 'blue',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'a black look',
		definition: 'An angry or a disapproving expression on somebody’s face.',
		question:
			"I tried to apologize for what I said, but she gave me such a  _____  look that I knew it wasn't the right time to talk to her yet.",
		a: 'green',
		b: 'yellow',
		c: 'red',
		d: 'black',
		correct: 'black',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'a pink slip',
		definition: 'A notice of termination from an employer',
		question:
			'He was in total disbelief when he received a  _____  slip from his boss today, as he had worked at the company for over a decade.',
		a: 'pink',
		b: 'blue',
		c: 'silver',
		d: 'orange',
		correct: 'pink',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'the men in gray suits',
		definition:
			'People working in politics, law, etc. who have power but are not known to the public.',
		question:
			'It will be the men in  _____  suits who decide whether the Prime Minister stays or goes.',
		a: 'white',
		b: 'gray',
		c: 'red',
		d: 'blue',
		correct: 'gray',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'red-handed',
		definition: 'In the very act of a crime, wrongdoing, etc.',
		question:
			'He tried to deny that he had stolen the money, but he was caught  _____  -handed by security cameras.',
		a: 'yellow',
		b: 'black',
		c: 'blue',
		d: 'red',
		correct: 'red',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'a (little) white lie',
		definition:
			"A lie thought to be insignificant and justified, especially one told to avoid hurting someone's feelings or giving offense.",
		question:
			'I didn’t like her new haircut, but I didn’t want to upset her, so I told a little  _____  lie instead.',
		a: 'black',
		b: 'brown',
		c: 'white',
		d: 'blue',
		correct: 'white',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'the brown bottle flu',
		definition: 'A hangover or sickness from drinking',
		question:
			"I'm not surprised you have the  _____  bottle flu today—do you remember last night at the bar at all?",
		a: 'brown',
		b: 'blue',
		c: 'black',
		d: 'white',
		correct: 'brown',
	},
];
